♪ In the not-too-distant
Future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
From you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
In a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
Cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
Didn’t like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We’ll send him
Cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
La-la-la ♪
♪ He’ll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we’ll monitor his mind
La-la-la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can’t control ♪
♪ Where the movies
Begin or end ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call
Cambot! ♪
- ♪ Pan left ♪
- ♪ Gypsy! ♪
- ♪ Hi girl! ♪
- ♪ Tom Servo! ♪
- ♪ What a cool guy ♪
- ♪ Croooow! ♪
♪ He’s a wisecracker ♪
♪ If you’re wondering
How he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
La-la-la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
"It’s just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000!" ♪
- Hoo-hoo!
- Thank you, thank you!
Hot show!
Hey, great to be here,
great crowd tonight.
- Thank you!
- Let’s hear it
from our musical director,
Servo Marcellus.
- Ooh!
- Hi, everybody.
Welcome
to the Satellite of Love.
I’m Joel Robinson,
and as you can see,
the bots are putting on
their own version
of the Tonight Show.
We’re just in time
for the monologue.
- So, what’s going on
in the news today?
Have you seen
that panty raids
are once again
all the rage at colleges?
I didn’t know
so many members of Congress
were going back to school.
( Chuckles )
I see the new Sharon Stone movie
is so steamy
it has to be edited
in order to get an "R" rating.
They had to cut out
all the scenes of Congress.
( Chuckles )
- Oh, Congress.
- I see the new poll says
the public objects to TV shows
that are about sex.
Hey, I like watching shows
about Congress.
- Hey, Crow,
you’d better knock it off.
You could get sued
for that, you know.
- Well, I’d hire a congressman
to defend me,
but they’re all out
having sex!
- Aw.
- Sex, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you.
Hey.
( Theme music playing )
So, does this clip need
any setup?
Who’s, who’s job is it
to set up Congress, heh?
- We’re done with that,
King Crow.
- Congress.
- Wilbur Mills and Fanne Foxe
are calling.
- They had sex.
- Joel, what would you say
if I told you
I’ve invented a low-cost,
low-maintenance household device
that could easily last
for a decade or more?
Say hello to Frank’s heart.
- You, you’ve invented
Frank’s heart?
- No, no, silly boy.
I’ve, I’ve harnessed
Frank’s heart.
I was cleaning the snakes
out of the pantry yesterday,
when suddenly it hit me:
nothing works harder
than the human heart,
especially when it’s clogged
with cholesterol.
Now, Frank’s heart was a mess,
and it’s getting worse
all the time.
The rest was easy.
Frank eats, I surgically attach
a generator to his heart,
and voila!
The cholester-do-all.
( Chuckling )
Oh, yes,
here you go, Frank.
- What’s going on?
- Yeah, right there.
Oh, and I’ve got to
whip you up some eggs, Frank,
and your turbine’s
slowing down.
So, eat some of that pie,
will you?
You see, it’s simple
and efficient,
and I can run a blender,
and a toothbrush,
( motor whirring )
and a room fan,
and a radio,
and a garage door opener,
and an arc welder.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Well, at some point
this will kill Frank,
but I think it’s worth it--
ha, ha--
an EKG,
does this work great.
( Chuckling )
Frank, eat!
Joel?
- Oh, sure, that’s great,
Dr. F, for you.
Anyway, up here
on the Satellite of Love,
where life’s generally
bright and cheery,
we’ve decided
that backwards masking
has gotten kind of
a bad reputation.
- It was surprising, really,
right under our noses,
thrash metal bands giving us
all backwards messages
to worship Satan
and the like.
Sheesh!
- So, we’ve come up
with back talk.
It’s a backwards masking
personal memo machine
that helps you remember things
subliminally.
- Right.
- First of all, start with
some nice, pleasant music.
( Music playing )
- Aw.
- There now, isn’t that nice?
- And simply tape your message
to yourself backwards.
- Right, let’s say
I’m an executive,
and I want to leave a memo
to myself.
I’d leave a message like this.
- Uh--
( SPEAKING BACKWARDS )
- Then the next day--
MACHINE VOICE: Ask Dan about
Fulbright contract.
- Ah, it’s fun!
- It is!
- We get to talk backwards.
Try it, Tom.
- ( Speaking backwards )
MACHINE VOICE:
Remember to tape Delta.
- Oh, this will be invaluable
for business persons,
students, homemakers,
teachers, cutlery salesmen,
congressional aides,
barbers,
rubber novelty
district representatives,
gym teachers,
that big guy.
- Uh, Crow.
- Hm?
- That’s plenty.
What do you think, sirs?
- The seventh inning stretch
to come...
DR. F:
Keep going, Frank.
I’ve still gotta vacuum
under the couch.
- And now True Value
hardware stores--
( frank choking )
- Oh, good one, Frank.
Joel, your movie today
is called "The Painted Hills."
It’s got Lassie--
yes, the dog--
starring as Shep,
another dog.
Oh, and there’s a hygiene short
that I was hoping
Frank would see.
Frank, I’d love to revive you,
but how can I,
when I can’t run
the defibrillator?
Frank?
MACHINE VOICE:
Dr. F is a butthead.
( Buzzer )
( Music playing )
( Chuckling )
- That’s great.
Oh, is there going
to be a test?
- What is this?
Is it an infomercial?
Where’s Cher?
- Body Care and Grooming.
They’re cops.
- You know what?
They should distribute
this film in Seattle,
where the grunge look
is so popular.
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, they need it.
( Music playing )
- And based on the book,
"Everything I Ever
Needed to Know,
I Learned at
the Beauty Parlor."
- It was the cleanest of times;
it was the dirtiest of times.
NARRATOR IN MOVIE:
Aw, spring--
- Filthy, shameful spring.
NARRATOR:
--when birds are on the wing,
when flowers bloom.
- And so do young men.
- Hm.
- This guy hasn’t a prayer.
( Chuckling )
- A young Frank Sutton
makes his move.
- Crow.
- You know, people
were whiter back then.
NARRATOR: Spring, when a young
man’s fancy likely turns to--
- Underpants.
NARRATOR: --thought.
- Oh.
NARRATOR: What’s the matter?
- Hm?
NARRATOR:
Exam week getting you down?
- Oh, leave me alone.
NARRATOR: What you need
is to put down that notebook
and take in some of
the beauties of nature.
- Pick up a rifle.
NARRATOR:
See what I mean?
- The Andrews Sisters?
No way.
- Hm.
NARRATOR: But wait a minute,
young lady.
How did you get
into this picture?
- My agent booked me.
NARRATOR: You see,
we’re trying to prove a point
about nature and beauty,
and you’re not exactly
helping, you know.
- Yeah, well, bite me.
NARRATOR: Look at your hair.
- I like her hair!
NARRATOR:
Look at that blouse.
- I’m looking, I’m looking.
NARRATOR: And the way that
skirt hangs and those socks.
- Look at that sidewalk.
Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk
NARRATOR: Sorry,
there must’ve been a mistake.
You don’t seem to be
exactly the type
to make this guy behave
like a human being.
- You know, to make him
grope you and paw at you.
- I’m late for my
Hitler Youth meeting.
NARRATOR:
But wait a minute.
- ( Speaking backwards )
NARRATOR:
Let’s start all over again.
- And find new ways
to shame her.
- Oh, brother.
- What the hell?
NARRATOR:
Oh, brother, is right.
Look at that hair,
that skin, that mouth.
- Those-- nose.
NARRATOR: And now look
at that blouse.
- We just took your libido
and starched and pressed it.
NARRATOR: And now look
at the skirt and the socks.
- Hey.
NARRATOR: Thanks a lot
for helping us prove a point.
- Now be gone.
NARRATOR:
And you--
you, too, know the value
of a good appearance.
- Excuse me,
I couldn’t help but notice
how much you look
like everyone else.
Heh, heh, heh, heh.
- Tackling her from behind
is the first step.
- Ten years later--
- This marriage
is suffocating me!
NARRATOR:
In fact, you all know
that a good appearance
is a must,
not only to your college
life now--
- This sucks.
NARRATOR: --but to your business
and professional lives later.
But good appearance
is more than dressing up
like a fashion plate.
- It’s looking like
Bruno Hauptmann.
NARRATOR: Anyone will make
a good appearance,
no matter what
his style of clothing.
- Even Larry Hovis.
NARRATOR:
Clothes are important.
- Mm-hm.
NARRATOR: Besides fitting well
and looking well,
the clothes should be
appropriate to the occasion.
- Hmph.
NARRATOR: Wearing inappropriate
clothes, like these shoes--
- Is immoral.
NARRATOR: --is a sure way
to make yourself uncomfortable
and conspicuous.
- Expressing individualism
is just plain wrong.
NARRATOR: But good grooming
is more than clothes deep.
- It’s being snowy white.
NARRATOR: Good grooming starts
with personal care.
- It starts with the soul.
NARRATOR: This principally means
the care of your hands,
hair, your teeth,
and your skin.
- And your naughty bits.
- Yes.
NARRATOR: Let’s begin with the
skin by taking a look at it
from the doctor’s point of view.
- Oh, yeah.
Oh, you’ve got a big
blackhead right here.
NARRATOR: You’ll find the skin
is a complex living tissue,
whose proper care
requires a basic understanding
of what it is
and what it does.
- But, doctor,
I twisted my ankle.
NARRATOR: In this highly
magnified section
through the skin,
we see that skin is made up
of various layers.
- You’ll see the path
of the motorcade was diverted--
NARRATOR: Individual cells
of the outer layer
are constantly drying out
and dropping off--
- Whoopee!
- Whee!
( Cheering )
- There we go!
- Yoo-hoo, catch me!
Ooh, aha, there I go!
NARRATOR: Skin differs
in thickness and texture
on various parts of the body,
such as on the lips.
- Ah!
NARRATOR:
The eyelid--
- We have a "Carnival of Souls"
here.
NARRATOR:
--or the feet.
Perhaps the most familiar
example of skin specialization
is on your fingertips.
- Hm.
NARRATOR:
Here the skin is grooved
to help you hold
smooth objects
- Out from the inkwell
comes Koko the Clown -
NARRATOR: Almost all skin
is richly provided with nerves,
which give the skin
an amazing sensitivity
to outside stimuli;
hence, the skin acts
as a sensory organ
for the protection of the body
as a whole.
- There, that’ll keep
the devil out.
NARRATOR: And skin serves to
protect you still another way:
by providing one of
the first physical signs
of illness or disease.
- That’s an Indian rub,
all right?
You got a little sister?
NARRATOR:
Most skin also contains hair.
The hair roots are located
below the skin surface.
- Wait a minute. The hair
has a liver and a spleen?
NARRATOR: ( indistinct )
hairs are found
in association with
the sebaceous or oil glands.
- There’s oil
in them thar skins!
Heh, heh.
NARRATOR: These oil glands
often empty directly
into the hair follicle
or opening--
--by means of which the oil
reaches the skin surface.
The purpose of this oil
is to soften and lubricate
the hair and skin.
- Hey, you can’t say lubricate.
NARRATOR: Another gland found
in the skin is the sweat gland.
- Right.
NARRATOR: Sweat glands
open directly into the skin
and discharge sweat through
individual openings or pores.
( Slurping noises )
NARRATOR: Sweating is one of the
chief functions of the skin.
The main value of sweating
is the control of body heat--
- Thank you.
NARRATOR: --brought about
by the evaporation of sweat
from the skin surface.
- Hi, I’m Wasty, the national
spokesman for sweat.
NARRATOR:
Most everyone sweats under
one circumstance or another.
- Ah!
NARRATOR:
Besides accumulating sweat,
the skin is also constantly
picking up dirt, dust, grit,
and other foreign particles.
- Skin sucks.
NARRATOR:
And because the skin has lots
of openings in its surface,
these foreign particles,
most of them
loaded with bacteria,
may enter the skin
and start an infection.
- On Lyle Lovett.
NARRATOR: Such an infection,
if untreated or irritated,
could develop into
a widespread inflammation
or even blood poisoning.
Don’t let this happen to you.
- Don’t change a tire
with your face.
NARRATOR:
Protect your skin.
Keep it looking
clear and fresh.
Keep it clean.
- Pickle it, varnish it,
soak it in vinegar!
NARRATOR: The best way
to clean your skin
is still the old-fashioned use
of soap, hot water,
and plenty of elbow grease.
- ♪ Your hand’s in the gutter
Your love’s in the sink ♪
NARRATOR: And the result
is well worth the effort.
You don’t need
scientific proof of it.
You can feel it.
- ♪ I feel pretty
Oh, so pretty ♪
NARRATOR:
In addition to soap and water,
there are other good aids
for cleaning your skin.
- ♪ Dominique, nique, nique ♪
( BOT HUMMING "DOMINQUE" SONG )
NARRATOR: One of these
is cleansing cream.
- One of these is nitric acid;
choose wisely.
NARRATOR:
Many girls find this helpful
in removing cosmetics.
- Many are just plain wrong.
NARRATOR: However, nothing
can take the place
of your daily bath or shower.
- Hm.
- You should never disrobe,
even in the shower.
- Mm-mm.
- I’m so nutty.
- Get in there.
- Nutty I am.
NARRATOR: This is the time
to give your skin a good,
invigorating workout.
( Bots making sounds
from "psycho" shower scene )
If there is no visible dirt
to wash off,
there are body odors
to be eliminated
by cleansing your skin
of dried sweat,
skin scales, and dust,
which accumulate constantly.
- We just used
that in the bowl, dear.
Oh, oh, never mind.
NARRATOR: Your bath or shower
should end with a brisk rinsing
to carry away
all soapy residue.
This is really
the best part of the shower.
It stimulates the skin
and wakes it up all over.
- Now get out!
You’ve wasted enough water!
Get out!
NARRATOR:
Bathing and toilet articles
should be kept
for your own personal use.
- Grooming is between you
and the Lord God.
NARRATOR: Don’t share them
with others.
- Don’t trust people;
they’ll only hurt you.
NARRATOR: You wouldn’t use
another person’s toothbrush,
so don’t use their towel
or toilet articles.
- Live a lonely, sheltered life.
Plotting, scheming.
NARRATOR: And it goes without
saying that only clean lingerie
should go next to
that clean skin.
- Oh, yeah, say that again.
- Oh, stop.
NARRATOR: While it may not be
necessary for all of you--
- It’s fine.
NARRATOR: --some girls use
a lubricating cream
or a lotion to prevent
skin roughness or chapping.
Expensive creams and powders,
however, aren’t necessary.
- Could you get
out of my room, please?
NARRATOR: A healthy skin
can be kept attractive
with only a few simple
preparations.
And so, the end
of a perfect day.
- An entire day
spent grooming.
NARRATOR: A few minutes
in the morning and evening
and occasional checkups
during the day
are all you need
to establish and keep up
good grooming habits.
- Thus ends a day in the life
of Ivan Denisovich.
NARRATOR: And you--
- Jezebel.
NARRATOR: --by following
these simple rules
of body care and grooming,
you, too, will have
that quality of appearance,
that feeling of well-being
so important to make
your dreams
of happiness come true.
- And, remember,
when you touch yourself,
the saints cry.
Goodnight.
- Keep watching
the medicine cabinets!
Keep watching
- You’re next.
- Oh, let’s not forget
these guys.
( Theme music playing )
- Lassie is back,
and she’s pissed!
"The Painted Hills,"
the Cristo story!
- What kind of an agent
do you have to have
to get your name
listed under Lassie?
- True Boardman,
not his real name.
- I’m afraid we’re going to be
true bored men after this.
( Chuckling )
- Hey, isn’t that the song
that Big Bird sang
about the alphabet?
- Joel, did you know that Lassie
couldn’t work with guilt,
so they brought in Lipstein?
- Oh.
- Did you know that?
- Well, let’s lighten things up.
- Yeah.
- You know, William Tuttle
always does Lassie’s makeup.
That’s always in the contract,
absolutely.
- Okay.
- Why do I have to go
to the bathroom all of a sudden?
- Uh-oh, sounds like
it’s going to be an epic.
- I’m not excusing you.
- Oh, is Lassie
going to teach us
good grooming techniques, too?
- Alive,
My Side of the Mountain,
The Eiger Sanction.
NARRATOR:
Who of us will ever know--
- Me!
NARRATOR: --what’s in the heart
of a dog?
- Heartworms.
NARRATOR: This is the story
of a great love--
- The greatest love of all.
NARRATOR: --the love of a dog
for one man--
- It won’t work.
- Mm-mm.
NARRATOR:
--a love that was to prove
even stronger than life itself.
- They’re married now
and live in these hills.
( Music/whistling )
- ♪ She ran calling wildfire ♪
MAN:
Hello, Shep!
- Hm?
- She’s got a deep voice
for a dog.
MAN:
Hello!
( Bot making wolf sounds )
MAN: Shep!
- Aww.
- Lassie won’t let
the director
photograph her other side,
you know.
MAN: Shep!
- Would you shut up?
I’m posing here.
( Shep barking )
- Snausages, Snausages.
- Heh, heh.
- Hm-- hm?
There’s trouble
on the "McKenna’s Gold" set!
JONATHAN:
Where are you, girl?
- Oh, now what?
You knuckle knobs-- jeez.
JONATHAN: Hurry up!
( SHEP BARKING )
Get me out of here!
- Hey, Grandpa did fall
down the well.
- What do you know?
- Hey, hey.
Never mind eating me.
Just get me out of here.
Start digging, go on.
- What, how’s that,
Mr. Weatherwax?
- That’s it.
That a girl.
Keep a flying. Hey!
- Oh, no, that’s my groin,
honey.
Don’t dig so deep.
- Hey, the other way,
the other way,
the other way, Shep!
No, no, go dig, dig.
- No, no, Shep.
- Dig, keep digging.
That’s million-dollar dirt.
We’ve hit it this time, Shep.
We’ve hit it sure.
No, keep going.
I forgot to peer the shaft up.
I’ve darn near been
the richest corpse
in the territory, ha, ha.
- He had sand on his lap,
and he needed help?
( CHUCKLING )
- Come on, girl.
We’re heading for town.
Just wait ’til you see
Frank Blake’s eyes
when we tell him
he’s a millionaire.
- You’re welcome.
( Music playing )
- ♪ Nothing to do
- ♪ Nothing to do ♪
- ♪ There’s nothing to do ♪
- ♪ Nothing to do
- Nothing to do ♪
- Oh, careful,
there’s a speed trap here.
( Shep barking )
( Children shouting )
- Thanks for the treaty, mister!
- Thanks for the continent!
- This was a time
when Denver Pyles
roamed the land freely.
- ♪ Ding ding ding
Ding ding ding ♪
- Eggnog--
make it a double.
- Well, Jonathan,
how are you?
Merry Christmas.
- And get your dog
out of here.
- How about it,
on the house?
- No.
- Well, how about you, pup?
- Jim Beam, rocks.
- Can’t call you pup anymore,
can I, fella?
- Can’t call her a fella,
neither.
- She’s neutered.
- Say, that’s right.
Excuse me, beautiful.
- She’s looking
right at his throat.
- Well, how’s it
going, Jonathan?
- Shep and me
ain’t complaining.
- Well, I am.
- Uh, Steve,
has Frank been around tonight?
- Frank?
Frank Blake?
Be right back.
- I’ll go see
if Miss Kitty’s here.
- Thanks, Steve.
Deal me out.
- Hi, folks.
- Jonathan Harvey?
- Hm?
- What, what is-- oh.
- That’s right.
I’m Lin Taylor.
- I love your work.
- Sorry we couldn’t
let you know, Jonathan.
Martha wanted to,
but there was no way
of finding you in time.
- Time for what?
- Frank’s dead, Jonathan,
over a month ago of pneumonia.
- Frank, hm.
Frank, hm, hm, hm.
Frank, hm.
- Tommy worries me, Jonathan.
- Tommy?
Who’s Tommy?
- Do you know
that he’s never once cried?
- Ah, just hit him
with a class ring.
- If he could just let it out.
- We’ll work it out, Martha.
We’ll find a way.
But right now,
what about this fella, Taylor?
- Lin’s a fine man.
He’s been wonderful.
- Why did Frank take him in
as a partner?
- He had to.
Lin’s buying in when he did
kept us from losing everything.
- I see.
- Now, who’s Lin?
- Does that make him a partner
of grub stake rights?
- Yes, why?
Jonathan,
you’ve made a strike!
- I’ve got something
to show you.
- No!
- Ooh!
- Oh, it’s okay.
( KNOCK ON DOOR )
It’s the feds!
- Now, is this the real old west
or the Roy Rogers old west--
- Come in.
- --where they had
electricity and cars.
- Lin, Jonathan’s inside.
I’m so glad you’re here.
Jonathan has something
to show us.
- He’s the world’s largest elf.
- Yeah.
Look at this.
- A piece of key lime pie, hm.
- I found a vein of that.
If it’s deep enough,
it could be the biggest strike
this territory has ever seen.
That’s why we’ve got to
file a claim and quick.
- File before it’s proved?
You file now and word gets out
that you struck ore like this--
- Who’s that guy?
- --every claim jumper
in the territory
will be in those hills
in a week,
before you’re sure yourself
if you’ve hit the main vein.
- By gad, you’re right.
Thirty years
of mud scrabbling;
and when I do find
the glory dust,
I go off half-cocked.
- But enough vernacular.
- Mr. Taylor--
- I love you.
- Martha’s right about you.
- You’re odd.
- And right now
you can start working
and being a partner
by lining me up some supplies.
- Of course, Jonathan,
anything you need.
- Meet you in the store
in a half hour.
- Yeah,
I live to serve you, Cal.
- Goodnight, Lin.
- What did he stop by for?
- If it’s all right with you,
Martha--
- I’d like to know
who that guy was.
- I’d like to talk right
with Tommy.
- All right, Jonathan.
If there’s anything you can do.
- Shame him, humiliate him,
whatever you think is best.
- I’m gonna snap this kid’s will
like an old pretzel.
( Sad music playing )
- Come on, now, cry, cry!
- Tommy.
- Can you hear me?
Can you feel me near you?
- What’s Rutherford B. Hayes
doing in this movie?
- Tommy.
- Hm?
Jonathan,
Jonathan.
- Jonathan.
- Oh, Jonathan!
Why’d he have to die?
- Ah, you must’ve done
something wrong, Tommy.
- I can’t say.
- I want my pa, Jonathan!
I want pa!
- You know,
his head just doesn’t have
the structural support
for that hair.
- Some things
we can’t answer, Tommy.
- God check time, Tommy!
- The Lord’s got His way
of doing things
that we just can’t answer.
- But Jonathan,
isn’t pre-determination based on
not an egocentric conception
of a--
- I didn’t want to cry.
- You go ahead and cry.
- You baby.
- Used to do it myself
sometimes,
before my tears
all dried up on me.
- Not like this.
- Now how about Shep here?
Those hills up there,
that’s no place for a dog.
- Hi, star of the film here.
- Least wise, not Shep.
- It isn’t?
- No, no, it’s too lonesome.
She likes folks around.
The fact is she’s just plain
ain’t happy up there.
- You guys talking about me?
- As for me, well,
I’m better off alone.
- That’s for sure.
- Lots of times,
the dog is nothing
but a darned bother to me.
- Oh, must you air
our dirty laundry?
- Bothers you?
Shep?
- Yeah-- you, Shep,
now go on, go on now.
Here, you get away.
Now go on, get away.
- Sorry, Tommy.
- Now, what I’m sand-washing
up to with all this is--
- Can you take over
her payments?
- How about taking her
off my hands?
- Oh, that’s a great replacement
for my father.
- Will you do it, Tommy,
will you?
- You’re an old liar, Jonathan.
- Hm?
- I can’t take Shep from you.
She’s your dog, nobody else’s,
’til she dies.
Thanks anyway.
And look,
don’t tell anybody I bawled.
- Sure, you little wuss.
- Will you, please?
- Honest to Christmas.
- Hey, everybody,
Tommy’s in there
crying like a little girl!
- We didn’t do so good.
- Look, I’ve really
gotta go outside.
- All right, it’s Christmas,
and giving
is part of Christmas.
- Snausages.
JONATHAN: Anyway, you are
a bother to me.
( Shep whining )
Ah, be quiet.
Don’t look at me that way!
- Tonight on "The Advocates,"
our debate will be about
the woman from today’s short.
Tom Servo and Crow T. Robot
will argue over
whether she’s more attractive
sloppy--
- Yes.
- --or clean.
- Clean.
- Representing sloppy
will be Crow.
- Yes.
- Representing clean
will be Servo.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- I will be your moderator.
The outcome will be decided
by Joel Robinson.
I now turn the floor
over to Crow.
( CLEARING THROAT )
- Uh, thank you, Gypsy.
I like her sloppy.
While her well-groomed,
in other words square,
classmates were listening
to Pat Boone and Patti Page,
she was at the local jazz club
grooving to Miles, Monk,
and Coltrane.
While her classmates
were struggling to make it
through an issue
of Reader’s Digest,
she was the only woman
on campus
who could freely quote
Henry Miller.
She may be sloppy,
but she fits neatly
into my idea of paradise.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
Tom Servo.
- ( CLEARING THROAT )
Thank you, Gypsy.
I like her clean,
’cause it just shows
that she wants to change
the system from within.
Sure, she’s a seething
cauldron of passion,
but she wears
clean underpants,
and she knows where her shirt is
in the morning.
Call her what you will:
a Scoop Jackson Democrat
or a Jacob Javits Republican.
Either way, she’s the stuff
that dreams are made of.
Thank you.
- Thank you, boys.
- Thank you.
- And now Joel Robinson
will render his verdict.
Joel.
- Well, thank you, Gypsy.
Uh, both of these issues
are complex,
and there are no easy answers,
but Crow is right.
- Woo-hoo!
I’m right, I’m right! Hoo-hoo!
- Look, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho,
whoa, whoa!
Wait a minute, Joel!
Now, the whole subject of
cleanliness and grooming
is very important to me,
and I know a much more
effective way
to resolve this issue.
- Well, uh, how’s that?
- A spitting contest.
( SHOUTING )
- Ow, ooh, oh, hey!
- Wait, wait.
Hey, knock it off. Hey!
( Theme music playing )
- Don’t even say it.
- But I wanted a super soaker.
- Aw, gee, that Jonathan.
- Well, that son of a--
ha, ha!
- Merry Christmas, Tommy.
- Merry Christmas, Ma.
Look!
- Yes, dear, I know.
- He’s got mange, distemper,
and lots of ticks.
- "Dear Tommy,
I put it up to Shep.
She agreed with me.
She’s yours.
Merry Christmas
from Jonathan."
Where is Jonathan?
- He’s dead.
Open your other gifts.
- He’s gone.
- Gone?
Is it all right, Ma?
Can I really keep her?
- That’s what he wanted, Tommy.
- Thanks, lady,
you were my last hope.
- Oh, man, shouldn’t have eaten
all those socks.
- Divorced, harassed
by creditors.
- Come on, pretend
that you like me, girl.
- Oh, man, I shouldn’t have
eaten all those socks, ugh.
( Thundering )
- Heathcliff, Heathcliff!
Arf!
( Humming tune from
"the great escape" )
- No one escapes
from Stalag 13.
TOMMY:
Shep, oh, Shep.
- Come on,
it’s dress-up time.
Tonight, you’re
Marlene Dietrich.
- Shep.
- You’re drunk, aren’t you?
Bad dog!
- What’s the matter
with you, Shep?
- I’m tired, okay?
- Ma!
Ma, something’s
wrong with Shep!
- Well, they shaved Shep,
and that’s all that’s left.
TOMMY: What’s wrong with her,
Mr. Bald Eagle?
- Please, it’s Bald.
TOMMY: What’s wrong?
( Speaking native language )
- Huh?
- He said dog Shep not eat,
because she wants to go home.
- To Jonathan?
- I gave you the best years
of my life.
( Speaking native language )
Jonathan.
- He say dog starve until die
if not go Jonathan.
- Must drag butt
across driveway.
- Thanks, Mr. Bald Eagle.
Thanks.
- Lassie can get dressed now.
- Goodbye, Red Wing.
( Speaking native language )
Ma, we’ve gotta get her
to Jonathan.
Please say I can take her.
Please, Ma.
- Maude?
- Well, I don’t know, dear.
- Oh, hi.
- How could you ever find him?
- Shep could.
She knows where the claim is.
- I’ll ride her there.
- But you still
couldn’t go alone.
- I’ll take him, Martha--
be glad to.
- He’s hot for
the widow Martha.
- Gee, thanks, Mr. Taylor.
- Aw.
- Did you hear that, Shep?
We’re going to take you back
to Jonathan.
Now you’ve gotta eat
and get strong for the trip.
- Look, I’ve got a lot of
other things on my mind.
- Here, take some.
You’ve got to.
- Come on, it’s milk of
human kindness, two percent.
- He’s not mine, but I let him
live with me, heh.
- Ma, look!
She’s eating!
She’s gonna be all right!
- Now, look,
if you keep this down,
you can have some soda crackers
and watch "That Girl."
( Shep barking )
- ♪ The biggest sky
You ever saw ♪
♪ Was in Seattle
Do-do-do-do-do ♪
- He only lived
a couple of blocks away.
- That’s not exactly
the incredible journey, is it?
( Shep barking )
- Shep, what is it?
Jonathan!
- It’s a cabin,
you little turd.
- Jonathan.
JONATHAN:
Here, Tommy.
- Jonathan, what’s wrong?
- Hm?
JONATHAN:
Fever.
It hit me a week ago.
- Match sure lit up the room.
- The worst is past.
- Quick, get him
a bowl of milk.
- So weak, I couldn’t
get food any longer.
- That’s what was
wrong with Shep.
She knew.
She wouldn’t eat.
She made us bring her here.
- No, you’re reaching, Tommy.
- Ma’s right, Jonathan.
Shep’s your dog
and nobody else’s.
So, I’m giving her
back to you, right now.
- Never mind the dog, Tommy.
- Here’s the Sex Pistols.
- Tommy,
you rustle up some wood.
I’ll see about the food.
- Well, we worked
the scam again.
We get another free meal.
- I’m all right, girl.
- I just got into
a bad deer carcass.
- And thanks.
- Taylor--
- Pass the salt.
- I guess you wonder how
our partnership’s been going.
You were right.
I’d have been a fool
to file that claim.
The vein petered out
in a week.
- That’s great.
You got any Mrs. Dash?
- So, I just kept
working upstream.
- Working?
- Simple stuff,
hardly worth a man’s time.
- How’s the Dinty Moore?
- I’ll show you.
Tommy, go on over there
by the shelf.
- Grab the teapot
and come after me.
JONATHAN:
Now slide that chest out.
The board underneath
will lift up.
- Get my magazines out.
JONATHAN:
Take them out.
- Then you go in there
and shut the top.
- Is there a point to this?
- Look inside, Tommy.
- Do it!
- What are you gonna do
with all this Bisquick?
- How much is here, Jonathan?
- Oh, not much;
only around about 6,000.
- $6,000?
- No, drachmas.
JONATHAN:
There’s plenty more to come.
- 6,000.
- That bass boat
I’ve been looking--
- You say
that’s just from gravel?
You still haven’t found
the main vein?
- No, but it’s up there.
I aim to just work upstream
until I find it;
and I will, as sure as
your name is Lin Taylor.
- My name is Tom Wopat.
- Jonathan, do you realize
what this means?
- It means we’re rich,
all of us.
- Sure, we are, but that’s not
what I’m talking about.
You need help.
Now, look, I’m starting back
to town tomorrow.
I’ll take this gold and deposit
it in all our names.
It’ll be safe there,
and I’ll be back.
Why, with proper equipment,
we can take that gold out
ten times as fast.
- Sit down and eat your stew.
- All my life I’ve waited
for something like this,
and I’m not taking any chance
on losing it now.
- Grated cheese?
- Mount Rushmore
before it was built.
- I just love these
new age type nature tapes.
They’re so relaxing.
- And a rapid runs through it.
- We’ll run the inlet channel
across there
and build a smooth spot
below the rapids.
- I love movies
where they slowly
assemble the plot like this.
- Now, what did we build again,
Steve?
- Let her go, Tommy!
- Well, look,
Shep is Tommy’s supervisor.
- Hm.
- We invented
the first water flume!
It’s fun!
- Ha, ha, ha.
- Ha!
- We’ll see one day’s take
from this baby, Taylor.
Just wait.
- How long do I have to wait?
- First thing I’m gonna do
is buy me a montage, yeah!
- Yee-hoo!
- This bites.
- Snausages!
- What is it
we’re doing again?
- Kenny Rogers as Moses.
- Industry!
- Any Snausages in there?
- Come on, work!
( Music playing )
- Rutherford B. Hayes
strikes it rich!
- Whew!
- Santon!
- I feel damp all over.
- It’s fun!
- The world is dying.
- What? What?
( Music playing )
- Well, looks like the montage
finally blew over.
( Theme music playing )
- Hey, it’s Juan Valdez.
- Hey, it’s someone else.
- The Denver Pyle look
was very popular this year.
- We’re being ransacked
by Tom Bombadil.
( Humming "bombadil" )
- Finally,
sweet Metamucil.
There’s the pretty underthings.
( CHUCKLING )
- Go get it!
Go get what you put
in that saddlebag!
- Solzhenitsyn?
- Oh.
TAYLOR: For days,
you’ve been watching us,
but you didn’t fool me.
I knew you were out there.
You heard what I said. Move!
- Come on, Kringle!
- Go on. Go get
what you put in there.
- Taylor!
What’s going on here?
- You keep out of this,
Jonathan.
I know what I’m doing.
- Don’t shoot my doppelganger.
- Will you get it,
or don’t you?
- You crazy fool!
I ought to lay you low!
- Make him show you
what he put in that saddlebag.
- I took something
from there for this house.
- He’s lying.
Look for yourself.
- No, Taylor, you look.
- No, you look.
- You first.
- Ah.
- Hm?
- He’s Gideon!
- Huh, he was already
sent out, huh?
- But he was inside,
searching around, snooping.
- For food!
I would’ve prepared a table
in the presence of my friends.
- Oh, you’re so holy.
- Oh, my mistake.
- This is Pilot Pete, Taylor.
- Pile On Pete?
- If you’d been long
in these hills,
you’d never have made
that mistake.
Don’t make it again.
Come on, Pete.
- Pile on.
- Let’s see about that supper.
- You a regular parson,
Mr. Pete?
- Regular?
- No, son.
Reckon I’m as irregular
as they come.
- Eww!
- Gotta have roots
to be a regular parson.
- I’m a heretic.
- Me, I ain’t got the roots
of a tumbleweed.
Two things I love
above all else.
- Larry and Balki.
- The Lord’s mountains
and the Lord’s sinners.
So, I spend my time in one
looking for the other,
and I sure find them.
- I’m a lawn gnome
in the summertime!
- What? I’m right here.
You better leave Shep alone.
She never makes up
to strangers.
- She don’t?
Here, here, lady!
Here, lady!
( Bot growling )
- Well, you’ve got her wrong,
Brother Taylor.
Thou sawest the beast that was
and is not, Revelation 17:8.
Why, there’s plenty of love
in this dog
for them that loves her.
Ain’t there, Shep?
Or maybe she just
likes my stew.
- Book of me,
chapter 4, verse 12.
- Heh!
- Pete--
- Give me my underthings back.
- This is from all of us.
- It’s a carrot.
- Well, in His name,
I thank you, Jonathan, Tommy,
Mr. Taylor;
and you, too, lady fair.
- The name’s Shep.
Remember it!
- The Lord be with you
in all your labors.
- And also with you.
- Lay not up for yourselves
treasures on earth,
but lay up for yourselves
treasures in heaven.
- In an interest bearing CD.
- Matthew 6:19.
- Got the half.
That’s a little preacher joke.
Well, I’m off
to the King Lear convention!
- Get up, Gabriel!
- So, this guy comes in,
stops the plot cold and leaves.
- Yep.
- Bye, Mr. Pete.
- Goodbye, Pete.
- Goodbye.
♪ Work for the night
’tis come ♪
- ♪ Work for the union label ♪
- ♪ Work through
The morning on ♪
- All right, new rule.
No crusty old evangelists.
PETE: ♪ Work while the dew
is sparkling ♪
- Tommy, you go down to work.
- Wook?
- I’ll be along.
- Do you mind explaining
yourself, please?
- Well? You gave him dust.
That’s a dead giveaway
we struck pay dirt.
The old fool talks--
- He won’t.
- I’ve seen to that.
- Pete knows the law
of these hills, Taylor,
and he lives by it.
You could try doing the same.
- Yeah, try piling on once.
- Until you do,
I’m taking that gun.
- I keep my own gun.
- You’re edgy, Taylor,
and getting worse every time
more gold is under that floor.
It ain’t just being scared
someone will steal it, neither.
It’s having to split
it with Martha and me.
- You’re crazy.
- "Only a quarter,"
you keep thinking to yourself.
"I only get a quarter of it,
and Jonathan gets half."
That keeps
eatin’ at you, Taylor.
I’ve been watching you,
and I know.
That’s why I’m
taking that gun.
- Let’s not fight
in front of the collie.
- No, you won’t do that.
There’s two reasons
why you won’t shoot me, Taylor.
- Three!
- The first, you won’t find
that vein without me;
and the other,
the other is just a hunch
that you haven’t got the guts.
- And the third?
Oh, I forgot where I was.
- Uh, would this be a bad time
to bring up Snausages?
- I was born in the house
my father built.
- Oh, man, I’m turning into
Victor French!
- It snowed.
Should we be working?
- There’s a lot of closet space
in this cabin, huh?
- Hey, his pajamas are just like
his clothes, heh, heh.
- Ah, the violins
are urging him on.
- The pistol.
- Well, he’s got
child-bearing hips.
- Jonathan, Jonathan,
can I get a glass of water?
- Oh, oh, yes.
Oh, I just have to
touch that hair.
Oh, soft.
- He’s gonna kipe
his copy of "The Firm."
- Ooh, ooh, ooh.
( SHEP GROWLING )
- No, no, cut, cut!
No, Lassie, it’s more of a--
( bot imitating
fierce growling )
( SHEP GROWLING )
- I said put it back!
- Hmph, well, okay,
I think I can stand up,
and walk over here,
and sidle over to the door,
open it up, and run!
- Works every time.
Ha, ha, ha!
- Heh, heh, now we rock.
- Good girl.
- Hey, my reward.
Squeaky newspaper,
Gaines-Burger,
Snausage,
anything, huh?
- Well, he didn’t see
the good grooming short, did he?
- Don’t think so.
- Look, Big Foot
putting on a blazer.
- Huh.
- And so the little fellow
fled the vicious cabin.
- Stallone in "Cliffhanger."
- Ah, he’s gotta be careful,
or he might fall right into
that matte painting.
- Oh, that’s dangerous.
( Suspenseful music )
- Well, this is far enough.
I guess I can go here.
- Heh, I guess
that convenience store
isn’t so convenient.
Ha, ha.
- Note to myself: "Next time,
go the way you know."
( Suspenseful music )
- Huh?
- Hey! Ride ’em.
( Suspenseful music )
- Oh, man, is it tough
to get to the fourth tee!
- Ooh.
( Suspenseful music )
- Leon Trotsky
in the action adventure
you thought
he’d never make.
( Suspenseful music )
- Well, back to the cabin.
- Oh, oh, I thought
that was a matte painting.
Good thing I didn’t fall.
- All right, about time
for that Nut Goodie.
- Heh, heh, heh, heh.
- Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Why am I doing this?
- This old mountain.
( Theme music playing )
- With an ice pick
through the skull,
thus bringing to a brutal end
the passionate life of one
Lev Davidovich Bronshtein,
Leon Trotsky.
Thank you.
- Oh, wow!
- Gypsy,
that was terrific!
- Oh, thank you, guys.
- It was riveting!
- Oh, thank you.
- Oh, hi, everybody.
Welcome to
the Satellite of Love.
We’re just finishing up
this week’s
term paper assignment,
the topic being
"Famous Figures in History
that Look Like the Cantankerous
49’ers in Today’s Film."
I did one on Aristotle.
- It’s excellent, by the way.
- Tom Servo did a hilarious
send-up of the Smith Brothers.
- You should’ve been here.
I did both parts.
- Yeah-- and now
that we’re all done,
it’s time for
Ovaltine and popcorn.
- Oh, I just love Ovaltine.
- Hey, hey, what about me?
Hey, what am I,
burnt toast here?
- Oh, I’m sorry, Crow.
And now Crow T. Robot.
- Uh, uh, put my study aid up.
- What?
- My study aid.
It fell down.
Put that up.
- Oh, okay, all right.
- Oh, and, uh, Cambot,
cue that music, please!
( CLEARING THROAT )
Rutherford B. Hayes.
Rutherford B. Hayes was born
humbly to his own son,
Rutherford B. Hayes, Jr.,
in Delaware,
while it was still Ohio,
sometime after
the French Revolution.
Rejecting a career
as a professional speller,
he was admitted to the bar
in 1845,
though he did not drink
lustfully from it.
- Uh-huh.
- Serving heroically
in the Civil War,
Hayes admitted later
that it was in the army
he first tasted human flesh.
In 1876, Hayes beat Bill Tilden
in a three-set quarter final
at Flushing Meadows,
which caused
the electrical college
to declare him
President of the United States.
- Uh, Crow, you just kind of
threw this together, didn’t you?
- Please, Joel, I’m quoting
from the World Book,
chapter H.
- Huh.
- ( CLEARING THROAT )
Here are a few of the highlights
of the administration
of Rutherford B. Hayes.
- Mm-hm.
- In 1877,
reconstruction ended,
and Jaques Derrida was named
Secretary of Linguistics,
and the era of deconstruction
began and continues to this day.
- I just don’t think that--
- Thomas Edison invented
the pornograph,
beginning the age
of pornography.
President Hayes
then passed the Hayes Act,
started the Hayes Office,
won fame
as an American lyric tenor,
and was named Archbishop
of New York in 1919.
- I think he’s lying!
- No, I’m not.
( Clearing throat )
After he retired,
he founded the original ZZ Top,
with James Garfield--
- Oh, yeah.
- --and Chester Alan Arthur,
shocked the world
with a publicity stunt,
when, on a bet,
he made a tent
out of the underwear
of William Howard Taft--
- Oh, come on!
- --and lived inside
for a full year.
Well, he did.
- Yeah.
- And in later years,
Hayes retired from the stage
and did a series of memorable
character parts in Hollywood.
Who can forget the time he was
slapped by Jacqueline Bisset
in the 1971 Universal movie,
"Airport"?
( LAUGHING )
- Who was that?
- And then after inventing
ringworm, Hayes died.
His last words were,
"I have only one life to live;
let me live it as a blond."
The end.
- Whew.
- Oh, and his blood type was AB.
The end.
- Sad what the mind can do,
isn’t it?
- Yeah, I’m gonna have to
hold you back a year, Crow.
- Cool.
Can I have my same desk?
( Alarm going off )
( Shouting )
- Rutherford B. Hayes.
- I want you to take this
to your Ma.
- Rutherford Hayes
all through my brain!
- Tell her I said we’re
going to file it right away.
It’s a description of the claim
made out in all our names--
hers, Taylor’s, and mine.
- Is there anything wrong,
Jonathan?
- No, this is just in case
someone gets the bright idea
to file it only
in their own name.
( Bots whispering )
- Oh, Mr. Taylor.
- But remember,
whatever happens,
not a word to anyone
about my doubt, even your ma.
Promise?
Now, come on,
hightail it.
Hurry up.
- Yeah, and if you run into
Pile On Pete, don’t look at him.
- Tell your ma not to worry.
- I will.
Bye, Jonathan.
- Oh, oh, and bring me back
some OJ and a Cosmo magazine.
- Shep, where are you?
Shep, what is this?
- I ate some gold.
- What ails you?
You know, between us, we’ve
got to take care of that boy.
He don’t know these trails
like we do.
Oh, it ain’t for good
this time.
You’re coming back.
Now go on, git.
- Yes, master,
I’m your total slave.
( Shep barking )
- There goes one stupid dog.
- Jonathan!
Jonathan...
- I set a trap for you and-- oh.
Where are they going?
- I sent Tommy home.
The kid’s getting lonesome
for his ma.
What’s all the excitement?
- Jonathan, that vein
we’ve been looking for--
if it was up there,
what would it look like?
- Well, uh--
- No, I’ll tell you.
The sheer face
of the cliff,
white cords,
the whitest you ever saw;
and in it,
jagged like lightning,
a vein of pure gold.
Gold, Jonathan, that wide.
It’s up there.
So help me, I found it.
It’s up there
waiting for us!
- Where?
- At the head of the canyon,
way up.
- Well, let’s go.
- It’s where I’m gonna
kill you.
Ooh, I can never
keep a secret.
( Shep barking )
- How do you work
this crazy thing?
( Suspenseful music )
- Come on. How stupid
are you feeling today?
( Shep barking )
- The British are coming!
Get away from me, dog.
The British are coming!
Would you just get away?
The--
- It’s the Von Trapp
family prospectors.
- Go on, Shep!
Go on back!
Home, girl!
- Wait a minute!
- Go back!
- What? I’m a dog!
I can’t process
this much information at once!
- Look, I’m 100 years old.
Where is this thing?
- You were sure right
about the mountain goats.
- Yeah, you said it.
- Now let’s see
if these two sequences
relate to each other.
- Go ahead.
- Make my day.
- Ooh, your hands
are really soft.
( Shep barking )
- Come on,
I need to use the bathroom!
Is this the right place?
- Oh, he didn’t make my bed.
Typical.
You know, there’s a shuttle bus
that goes here.
- Oh.
- Gotta get that stupid
bathroom key.
- Man, he’s really making him
work for his death.
- Heh, heh, heh.
- It’s the ledge just beyond.
( Suspenseful music )
- Let’s go.
- Come on over here.
This is where
I put the loose rock
for you to step on.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes, oh, yes, yes.
- Oh, I failed
to take into account
that he only weighs
63 pounds.
- Well, where is it?
- Son of a gun...
You know what?
It’s back a ways.
( SNIFFING )
- Obsession.
- Taylor!
- So, how much further?
- Taylor, help me!
Taylor, for God’s sake,
you can’t!
Help me!
- I haven’t the guts.
Remember, Jonathan?
- Oh, throw that in my face!
- Help!
( Jonathan screaming )
- How am I gonna explain this
in just barks?
- Now, lunch.
Oh, poopy.
Where did I put that rock?
Oh, boy.
( Suspenseful music )
- Oh, oh, hi, you.
I bet you’re wondering
what I’m doing up here.
TAYLOR:
Hello, Shep.
- This is where Shep’s
mastery of the stiletto
comes in handy.
- Look, I don’t even
want to talk to you.
- Here, Shep, come here!
- A lifetime of Snausages,
or I sing like a canary.
- What’s the matter with you?
- Uh, Mr. Weatherwax,
what’s the matter with me here?
I don’t know. Do you?
My trainer says
I’m not allowed to talk to you.
- I don’t think his testimony
will hold up in court.
- Mm-hm.
- Oh, he’ll probably be
in a wheelchair,
and I’m gonna have to
push him around.
Oh, geez, he looks like
Pile On Pete’s stew.
- It’s like Batman in reverse.
- Mm-hm.
- Thank you, citizen.
- Great, first I’ve gotta dig
him out of the dirt,
and he slides down
a dang mountain.
Aw, forget it.
Time to get a new master.
- Cinnamons.
- Like I always say, a dog’s
got to know her limitations.
- Ah, now, lunch.
- Tyrone Power
has a sleepless night.
- No, no, no, Pile On,
no, please, no.
- It’s payback time.
( Shouting/applause )
- Cool.
( Sniffing )
- Is that a bacon
and Snausage omelet?
What the?
( Shep sniffing )
- That’s where Jonathan’s butt
used to be.
- Hello, Shep.
- You can’t talk to me.
I saw what you did.
- Where have you been all day?
Looking for Jonathan?
- No, I caught a matinee
of "Oh, Heavenly Dog."
- I’m afraid
he won’t be back, Shep.
That doesn’t mean
you and I can’t be friends.
How about it?
- Look, just let me work
through my grief right now.
- Better be my way, Shep.
- Or the highway.
- I’d rather not have
anything happen to you.
Might make things
harder for me to explain.
- No, no, no,
don’t talk to me!
Stay on your side
of the room!
- Oh, look, if you don’t--
I’m talking to a collie.
Geez, I am freaking out.
- Uh, let’s see,
my cash card, my keys.
Lassie, you,
you seen my wallet?
- Oh, that’ll help,
since there’s no glass
in the window!
- I’m walking out this door,
Lassie,
and I’m never coming back.
- I hate my roommate so bad.
( Wolf howling )
- I hear you, man.
- Othello.
( Wolf howling )
- I left the iron on!
- Wait a minute!
I’m in "Seven Brides
for Seven Brothers."
Oh, Shep.
Oh, I’ll have to
clean that up later.
( Bot humming )
- Oh, I don’t want to see this.
- Get away from there!
Get away, I tell you!
- No!
- Hey, I’m a dog.
Come on.
- I said get away from there.
( Shep growling )
- I’m saying--
( BOT GROWLING )
- Get away,
or you’ll get what he got.
- Rave on, sister.
All right, woman.
- Okay, okay,
you can have the body,
but I get the gold.
( Shep growling )
- I don’t feel like fetching!
- Looks like he buried the old
guy and his hat separately.
( Shep growling )
- Lambada,
the forbidden dance.
( Lin screaming )
- Snausages.
- Seven o’clock already?
- Great, now a series of
very painful rabies shots.
- Oh, Lassie,
come out and play!
- I love to watch him squirm.
- Dope, you walked
right past me.
- I miss Lassie.
( Shep whining )
Ah, I’ve gotta get that dog
her own key.
- Hello?
Hi, I’m from PETA.
Ah, you’re probably mad.
Look, I was drunk last night.
I’m sorry.
- Hungry, huh?
( Shep whining )
I figured that would
bring you around,
and I’ve got something
all ready for you.
- Gonna be a Snausage, right?
Oh, please,
let it be a Snausage.
- Oh, I put up
a lot of poison last year,
but now we’re just down
to the one jar.
- It’s a deadly game
of cat and mouse,
only with a dog and a man.
- You know, the 1800’s
were a golden age of gravy.
- Aw.
- Here, I hope you like
your Fritos.
- Oh, no, I had poison
last night.
- Hey, that’s good poison.
- Not hungry enough yet, huh?
You will be.
- I believe I ordered
a Greek salad.
Uh, can I just have
a rye crisp, please?
- Little does he know
Lassie switched food.
He’s eating Kal Kan!
( Shep whining )
- You know, Lassie’s
not really that hungry.
She just dug up Jonathan
and, well, uh--
- Oh.
- Hm.
- That’s an odd taste.
Oh, I can’t stay mad at you.
- Is this what you want?
( Shep barking )
- So that’s the way
it is, huh?
- Mm-hm, mm-hm.
- Here.
( Shep barking )
- Mm-mm. Souvlaki?
( BOT LAUGHING SINISTERLY )
- More?
( Shep barking )
- Puppy Chow for a full year
’til he’s full dead.
- Oh, no, get the Ipecac.
- Eat it.
- Now get out of here.
Get out!
And remember,
you asked for it.
- Go die.
Die outside now.
Come on.
- Yeah, I thought so.
I get better service
at Planet Hollywood.
- He’s not gonna die, is he?
- Oh, yeah, she’s toast.
Old Lassie dead, dead, dead,
deader than a door nail, yep.
- Oh, this is where Lassie
gets the inspiration
for her poetry.
- Dude, she’s gonna die.
- Boy, do I feel stupid.
It’s more my pride that hurts.
( Shep whining )
- Come on,
it’s gut chuck time, Lassie.
Find it, find it!
Oh, there she is,
200 yards.
You could make it
with iron sights,
but you want to
use a scope, Crow.
- Hey.
- Geez, a river runs through it,
and grapefruit runs through me,
I tell you, oh.
- I can’t believe
I ate the whole thing.
- If I could just burp,
I’d feel better.
( Shep whining )
- Oh, she’s a goner.
Probably having hallucinations,
right now,
a little wagon coming out
of the kitchen cabinet.
( Chuckling )
Yep, two paws in the grave.
- Hey, stop it!
- I’m just being a realist,
Crow.
- This exercise will give
your dog buns of steel.
- What is this?
Camille?
- I don’t know.
- Crawl!
Come on,
you’ve never given up
on anything in your life!
Crawl!
( Making silly sounds like
curly of the three stooges )
( Shep whining/barking )
- I’m coming, Elizabeth.
I’m coming to join you.
- I don’t drink near the horses,
personally.
- You know,
that little puppy’s dead, too.
- Oh!
- Sorry.
( Shep whining )
- Boy, is she milking
this thing.
- Oh, don’t you
chew the scenery.
Don’t you--
drop it, drop it.
- Hey, I’m dying over here!
- Lassie,
does that really help?
- When she’s dying,
she’s going to take as many ants
with her as possible.
- Would you keep it down?
Oh, the great Lassie
is in trouble.
Well, I’ve stood in your shadow
long enough!
Lassie’s been drinking again.
- You know, they’re probably
dead, too, in fact.
- Tom, that’s enough.
- Sorry.
- He’s helping.
He’s pumping her stomach.
- I need bicarb
and a hot needle here, stat!
Come on!
( Small dog barking )
- Well, now he’s massaging
her heart, oh.
( Small dog barking )
- ( Speaking in
native language )
- Yeah, that’s Indian,
all right.
- Gibberish.
- I can hear the ocean roar.
- ( Speaking in
native language )
- His tag says he’s allergic
to penicillin.
- Hold on.
- Oh, yeah, nice heft.
This hide should bring in
ten bucks in town.
- Natalie Wood.
- Now, these are scenes
we didn’t see in
"The Searchers."
- Bald Eagle in town.
Find quick.
Maybe he save dog.
- It’s a tribal
Pippi Longstockings.
( Shouting )
( Bot whistling like siren )
- ♪ Sobbin’ women ♪
♪ Them sobbin’,
sobbin’ women ♪
( Shouting )
- Huh?
- All his woodland friends
are coming to help him.
( Bot humming excitedly )
- ( Speaking in
native language )
- Hi!
Hey, what’s going on?
- Oh, I saw them march down
at the post office.
- Oh.
- ( Speaking in
native language )
- Is that Russell Means?
Ha, ha.
- Good heavens, boy,
you’re right.
Oh, no, poison souvlaki.
- ( Speaking in
native language )
- Yeah, go get Jeff Chandler
and Joey Bishop.
- Who am I gonna bill for this?
Wait a minute!
( Theme music playing )
- This’ll help,
a feather in a dilly bar.
- ( Speaking in
native language )
- Oh, wait,
I was doing a bar mitzvah.
- Sorry, kid,
doesn’t sound good.
- Well, she will make
an attractive rug.
- Hey!
- Sorry.
- Please, Mr. Bald Eagle.
Isn’t there anything else
you can do?
- Well, I can do impressions.
( Making silly sounds like
curly of the three stooges )
- Well, this is
cross-cultural, isn’t it?
- Uh-huh.
- Are those Snausages
over there?
( Shep whining )
- Shep, Shep, girl.
Mr. Bald Eagle,
you’re wonderful.
Thanks--
( speaking native language )
- That’s outrageous!
I want to see
an itemized bill!
- ( Speaking native language )
- Wow, his teepee’s
really nice.
- I can’t tell you
how stupid I feel
about the whole poison thing,
Tommy.
- Don’t you worry, Shep.
- Okay.
- I’m gonna find out
about that poison.
Nothing’s gonna stop me
’til I do.
- This is God. Stop!
( Rumbling thunder )
- Oh, I just can’t get
this darn novel started.
- It’ll be really bad
while the weather holds.
- Hey, it sounds like
a Ken Nordine dream.
- One good stone
could start a slide
that would cover the gold
forever.
- The old man never said that.
- You can’t flash back to
something that never happened.
It’s not fair.
( Rumble of rocks sliding )
- Now the car’s rolling.
Is that me?
Am I making that sound?
( Rumbling thunder )
Boy, Dutch Elm
can strike quick.
- Hmph, dog gone,
don’t see that every day.
Well, back to the book.
- Vandalism.
Dang kids drink cheap wine,
listen to Anthrax.
Look at this.
Ah, hm.
Well, thank you, God.
Thank you so bloody much!
Hey, divinity.
( Bot humming theme song from
"2001: A space odyssey" )
( Suspenseful music )
- Oh, so that’s the lesson,
Joel?
Crime does pay?
- No, that’s not the lesson.
- No, the damage is done.
It’s in my memory banks.
Crime pays-- zip, lock.
- Look at that dog gone ridge.
- Hey.
- Shep’s back, and this time
it’s personal.
TOMMY:
Shep, come here!
- Shep--
TOMMY: Where are you going?
- You’ve got to write to
Mr. Eagle, a thank you note.
- The old guy is still alive,
’cause he had a straw with him
to breathe with.
- Or he’s a hellish zombie.
( Suspenseful music )
- Wait a minute.
These bags
are full of Snausages.
Lassie!
- Oh.
- It’s easier than balancing
your checkbook, believe me.
( Wolf howling )
- Oh, I’m a bad boy!
- Taylor is almost
wolfman-ish.
- Yeah, he gave himself
a Lilt home perm.
- Stay off the moors!
- Shep!
- Don’t kid yourself!
( Bots whistling )
- I’m looking for a man
with true grit.
- The bottom of the fifth,
and Lassie paces the mound
nervously.
( Whistling theme from
"lassie" tv show )
( Shep barking )
- Yeah, that’s it.
- This dog is dumb as a post.
( Shep barking )
- Here, puppy.
Come here, puppy.
Yes, puppy.
- What the?
Hey, if he shoots the kid,
all bets are off.
We’re gonna
trash the theater!
- Yep.
- I’m bringing home the baby--
oh.
- Jonathan.
- Tommy, what are you
doing here?
- What a mess!
What have you been doing here?
- Where’s Jonathan?
- He’s gone.
He’s been gone for three days.
- Where?
- I don’t know.
Over towards Blue Mountain
somewhere.
- Over to the mega mall.
- He went to pick us up a deer
for meat through the winter.
- Camp Snoopy.
- I heard his whistle.
- You couldn’t have.
- Shep must’ve, too.
She was barking.
- Where’d you see, Shep?
- Indian kids found her.
She was almost dead.
- I didn’t do it.
- From poison.
- But she’s all right now?
- Yeah, but I knew Jonathan
would want to know,
so I brought her back.
- Dang. I mean, good.
- Mr. Taylor, are you sure
he’s not here?
I know I heard.
- I told you, Tommy,
he’s not here.
- Please, sir,
may I have some more?
- Shep! Shep!
- Psst, hey, stupid kid,
I’m up here.
- Here, Shep!
Why won’t she come in?
I know she’s out there.
- Let me tell you about
the after life, Tommy.
- Don’t worry about her, Tommy.
You’re tired and upset.
A good night’s sleep,
and you can start home
in the morning.
Sit down now and rest.
- Tommy, you like refried
poison-- beans, beans!?
Oh, boy.
- I’ll fix you some supper.
( Sinister laughing )
- Well, cling peaches.
Button popped up,
but that’s okay.
- We’re having Beefaroni!
- Yeah, one gram of poison
per pound.
Hey, how much do you weigh, kid?
- I, I’d better unsaddle
my horse, Mr. Taylor.
I’ll be right back.
- I’d better think of a flimsy
excuse to leave, Mr. Taylor.
( Shep whining )
- Shep, what is it?
- It’s a grave.
- What is it, Shep?
- It’s a grave!
Do I have to draw you
a picture?
Look, here’s you, me,
this is the grave. Come on.
- Eww, gross!
- Jonathan.
( Shep whining )
- Shep, you killed Jonathan!
- Life is pain, Tommy.
- Yeah, well, anyway,
there’s more evidence over here.
Come on.
Come on!
( Shep barking )
- Oh, my God,
another grave!
Lassie’s got him
buried everywhere!
( Shep barking )
- Shep, be quiet.
- Come on, your poison’s
getting cold.
- Shh.
- Hm?
- Oh, Jonathan’s
dangerously skinny.
- Watch the prints, Tommy.
Heck, Ramsey needs that hat.
- Yes, it’s Jonathan’s.
- It has his stench.
TAYLOR:
Tommy?
- Can you hear me?
TAYLOR:
Tommy!
- Can you hear me?
( Suspenseful music )
- Tommy!
Tommy, you out here?
- He’s being followed
by a doughboy.
( Chuckling )
- Danged smoochers
on my property!
Come out, come out
wherever you are!
- Tommy!
Tommy, is that you?
- Tonight, Tommy goes
behind enemy lines.
( Humming them from
"the great escape" )
- Joel!
Servo went and melted me
into a golden god!
And it itches
a little bit.
- Meets the new gold standard,
Joel, yes.
Our very own Crow.
( Sinister laughing )
- Tom, Crow is not gold.
He’s gold tone.
I painted him gold.
- Yeah.
- Oh, you’d like me
to believe that,
wouldn’t you, Mr. West?
- You know, Tom, Crow is
basically a high density Kevlar.
That’s it.
- Yeah. Really?
- Yeah.
- Trying to head me off
at the pass, hey, Joel?
- Tom, listen.
If you break Crow down
into his essential elements,
he’s virtually worthless.
- Yeah-- hey.
- How stupid do you think I am,
old man?
Put ’em up.
- Listen, up here, snack items
have more value than Crow does.
You’d be better off
staking your claim
to a box of Bearwiches,
Tom, okay?
- The point is, Joel,
he’s gold, and he’s mine.
( Sinister laughing )
Together,
I can rule the world!
( Sinister laughing )
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, I’m really
worth a fortune.
In fact, I want me.
- Wait a minute.
- Yes, I’m mine!
I’m mine, all mine!
- Come on, dummy,
it’s time to extrude you.
( Theme music playing )
- Thank you for extruding me.
- Mm-hm.
- Sorry, Crow.
- No, no, let me go!
Let me go!
- Where’d you get it?
Where’d you get it?
- Craigie Way.
- It’s Jonathan’s!
You lied!
He isn’t away!
He’s dead!
You killed him!
He’s buried over there,
and you killed him!
- Shut up. Do you hear me?
Shut up!
- No, I won’t!
You killed him, and I’ll tell!
I’ll tell everybody!
- Oh, how could you
possibly tell everybody?
- You’re wrong, Tommy.
- You gonna tell the Chinese?
- You’re not gonna
tell anybody that.
- I’m gonna tell ’em.
- Shep, help!
- Shut up, you!
- Help, Shep!
- Ah, arf keba!
( Shep barking )
- Thanks, Shep.
I’m outta here. Good luck!
- Ah, Jim Collie!
( Shep barking )
- Dog tossing, tonight,
on "A Current Affair."
- Yeah, must’ve been
Lassie number 12 or so.
- When did they build a corral?
They used corral draw.
- Oh, you.
- Tommy!
- Come on, Apache, jump it!
- This must be
"Regional Velvet."
- Please, Apache,
you’ve gotta jump it.
You’ve gotta do it.
You’ve got to!
- Tommy, come back here!
Come back!
- Oh, you can’t expect him
to come back.
- Huh?
- Ah.
- So, when you’re the bad guy,
things just go your way.
Is that the lesson, Joel?
- No.
- You little fool,
I ought to--
- Oh, maybe I should see
if you’re alive.
Then I’ll kill you.
- Either this boy is dead,
or his heart has stopped.
( Suspenseful music )
- Kid, you’ve got
a French horn in your chest.
He can’t be dead.
He can’t be.
- Kaput, finis.
- Uh-uh.
- I love my dead, gay son.
- Uh, I, I, I, I, I, I--
( bots making sounds
like horse galloping )
- ♪ Now, when the west
was very young ♪
- Hey, look, he’s doing a shadow
thingy of Abe Lincoln--
Oh. Sorry.
- Now, wait, who is
that other shadow?
Is that Peter Pan
looking on?
- What a piece of work is man.
- Here, here’s some poison
for you.
- Now, come on, now, drink it.
- It’s Old Milwaukee.
- You’re all right now, here.
Drink, Tommy.
- Tastes as great as its name.
- Drink it.
That’s right.
- Taste it all--
one awesome calorie.
- That’s fine, boy.
- The first one is free, kid.
The next one’s on you.
- Yeah-- oh, and you were there,
and you, and you, and--
- Get away from me!
Leave me alone!
- Listen, son,
you’ve got to listen to me.
- I’m trying to redeem myself.
- There’s nothing
to be afraid of.
You’re here, perfectly safe,
and I brought you here.
- Just think,
no school ever again.
- Now listen.
You’ve been scared, Tommy.
I know that,
and it’s my fault.
- Because I tried to kill you.
- That’s, that’s because
I was scared, too,
so scared that I,
I almost lost my head.
- Here, look, I wet them.
Now do you believe me?
- A man can be scared, too,
Tommy,
even of a kid like you,
especially if that kid gets
the wrong idea in his head;
and you’ve got
the wrong idea, son.
- Yeah.
- You lied.
- You utterly lied.
- You said he was hunting.
- Yes, yes, I lied.
- You made me lie.
- Because I knew
you loved Jonathan, Tommy,
almost as much as
your own father.
So, I, well, I didn’t know
how to tell you just like that.
- Am I soothing you, Tommy?
- Jonathan is dead, son.
- And I helped.
- He was working up
in the canyon, and he fell.
- After I pushed him.
- It was an accident.
- Shep told me to kill him.
- Two days ago,
I found his body.
- And I laughed.
- Well, I buried it
where you saw.
- Oh, I buried him, yeah.
- I was coming in tomorrow
to tell your ma.
- If you want anymore facts,
you’ll have to speak
to my lawyer.
- Shep.
- Shep doesn’t like you, Tommy.
She told me that.
- Where’s Shep?
- Why, Shep’s all right.
I saw her outside
a while ago.
- She’s cool.
- Shep was like you, son.
- Bad.
- She got the wrong idea, too.
- Oh, yeah.
- So, let’s,
let’s both of us forget
about what happened tonight,
shall we?
- Bury it deep--
- Right.
- --real deep, Tommy.
- I guess so.
- Sure we will.
Now, you get some sleep,
and you’ll be fine
in the morning.
( Sinister laughing )
Just sleep, son,
and forget the whole thing.
- Mm, honk shoe
honk shoe, honk shoe, hm.
PETE:
Ho!
( Bots yelling like tarzan )
Hello!
- Hey, there’s a really loud
French guy out there.
- Hello there!
- Oh, no, Pile On Pete,
Pile On Jack, Pile On Roadie.
- Tommy, wake up.
- The Pile Ons are here.
- We have company, son.
And don’t forget what
we talked about last night.
About the accident
to Jonathan.
Better let me do
all the explaining, all right?
PETE:
Hey, Jonathan!
- What’s happening?
- Hi, Mr. Taylor.
Mel Steiner and Carl Crane.
- They’re with the DA.
- This runaway
come into their camp
over in Oak Flats last night,
and I thought I remembered
he was yours.
They was breaking camp
for winter anyway;
so, on the way into town,
figured we’d cut across
the ridge and fetch him back.
- Maybe pile on you.
- Why, hello, there,
Tommy boy.
- He’s a murderer!
- Hi, Mr. Pete.
Gee, I’m sure glad to see you.
- We both are, Pete,
mighty glad,
and thanks for bringing
the horse back.
- Sure. Where’s Jonathan?
- It’s a good thing
you men came along.
Come inside.
I’m afraid I’ve got
some bad news for you.
- Remember last week
when he was alive?
Well, that didn’t last.
PETE: And in thy
heavenly kingdom, Lord,
let him find peace.
- And let him pile on.
PETE: That peace
which passeth understanding.
- At least I don’t get it.
PETE: Let the gold he sought
on earth be his in heaven,
the pure and shining gold
of thy holy grace.
- Let’s skip a bit, brother.
- We ask it, Lord--
- Very slowly.
- --in His name, amen.
- Now the jets will fly
in the missing man formation.
( Bot making jet sounds )
- Well, custom says
we throw a handful of dirt,
but I’ve got a wicked idea.
- Oh, no, no.
- Come along, Tommy.
- Don’t pile on me.
- Let’s turn to a life of crime,
Tommy.
- Come on, Shep.
- Thanks, Pete,
and I’ll count on you
to explain everything in town.
- That I will.
- As long as you can take Tommy
and the dog back for me,
I’ll probably stay on up here
’til spring.
- Right.
TAYLOR:
For everyone’s sake,
I’d like to prove
Jonathan was right.
- Yeah, worked it.
TAYLOR: You see, he was sure
there was real pay dirt here.
- Rave on.
TAYLOR: So far,
we’ve never found it.
And, Pete, do all you can
to help Tommy, will you?
- Adults suck.
TAYLOR: You know, kids sometimes
imagine all sorts of things,
and Jonathan’s accident
hit the boy pretty hard.
- So did I.
TAYLOR:
I’m sure you understand.
PETE:
I do indeed, Mr. Taylor.
- Pete, he’s lying!
Don’t believe him!
Please don’t believe him!
It wasn’t an accident.
Jonathan didn’t fall.
He killed him.
I know he did.
Pete, he’s lying!
He’s lying about everything!
- Tommy.
- Kids say
the darnedest things, eh?
- The boy’s hysterical.
- He hated Jonathan,
and he killed him;
and last night,
when I found out,
he tried to kill me, too.
He’s lying, Pete.
- Tommy, listen to me.
You say
I wanted to kill you?
Where did you sleep
last night?
Who picked you up,
when your horse threw you,
and carried you to the cabin?
Tommy, you slept six feet from
me the whole night through,
safe and well.
- I didn’t even kill ya.
- Does that sound like
I wanted to hurt you?
Answer me.
- Pete, don’t believe him!
He did do it!
Shep knows, too.
That’s why he tried
to poison her!
- You want I should
pile on him here?
- You don’t believe me.
- Nope.
- He said the claim
didn’t pay out, but it did.
There’s bags full of gold
in that cabin, a dozen of them.
- If that’s true,
I guess you can show us, son.
- I will, come on.
- Mm, this is turning into
a parlor mystery.
I bet there’s gonna be
three different endings.
- It’s just as bright indoors
as out.
- Faced.
- There was more,
a lot more.
He’s done something
with the rest.
- He’s been eating coal a lot,
sorry.
- You’d better take these
back to Martha.
I was holding this,
hoping that I’d have
a bigger haul by spring.
- There is more now,
a lot more.
- Shut your hole, Tommy.
- Mr. Crane,
can’t you see he’s lying?
Mr. Steiner,
don’t believe him.
Please don’t believe him.
- I guess
we’d better be going.
- Please, Mr. Pete.
- Tommy, don’t.
You’re embarrassing me.
- Come along, son.
- You’ll be hearing
from my lawyer, kid.
We’re talking money.
( Music playing )
TOMMY:
Come on, Shep.
- I know where you live, Taylor.
Time to die.
- Lady, come on, come on.
- I’m barking like a canary,
Taylor!
- Never piled on a dog before.
- There’s not a pound
that’ll hold me, Taylor!
PETE: Lady, come on.
- I’ll be back.
( Theme music playing )
( Shep growling )
- Wild dogs can’t be broken.
TOMMY: Shep, come back!
Shep!
- You’ll never pile on me,
old man!
- The celebration
starts early.
( Shep barking )
- Oh, Mr. Shep, you have
a nasty habit of surviving.
- All right, throw the Snausages
out nice and easy.
( Gunshot )
Prepare to meet Kali.
- Mm, smart dog.
Took Taylor out of his season,
so he’s vulnerable.
- Hey, wait a second.
I think Barbasol had
an industrial spill.
- Oh.
( SHEP BARKING )
- That’s weird.
- Come on, dummy.
( GUNSHOT )
Woof!
Can taste the ozone
on that one.
Okay, the DA is supposed to
meet me here.
Ooh, ooh, that’s cold.
Oh, boy.
Oh, my dogs are killing me.
Ooh, ah, ooh!
This is no place
for a convertible!
- She’s taking him up K2,
see, because she’s a canine.
Watch out for squibs, Lassie!
Hey, Lassie got down
on all fours.
Let’s see this guy do that.
- Oh, look at all
the footprints.
They’re at a ski resort.
- Hm.
- Oh.
( GUNSHOT )
- Hey, what are you,
Claudine Longet?
- I know what you’re thinking.
Did I fire six shots
or only five?
Well, this film
is so poorly made,
it doesn’t matter.
( Shep barking )
( Bot making spitting sounds )
- I’m going to teach you
the meaning of arf.
- The Fido Sanction--
- Where beagles dare.
( Laughing )
- Three years later.
( Gunshots )
- Oh, now she’s gonna have
to be saved by a St. Bernard.
- Hm...
The most tedious game.
( Suspenseful music )
- Ugh.
- Hey, he’s turning into
Michael McDonald.
- That’s right.
- Stashed a bag of Cycle Two
up here somewhere.
Wait a minute.
Now, what was my plan?
I started chasing a rabbit,
and I forgot what I was doing.
- ♪ She came from somewhere
out of the long ago ♪
You know, it’s warm
in the foothills.
If you’re going out to
chase a dog today,
you might want to
take a jacket.
- Looks like a good place
to end this little charade.
- Uh, this is no good.
We’re on top of the monument.
- You know, they did
a lot of takes there.
- This is where
Holmes met his end,
at Reichenbach Falls.
- Oh, yeah,
Reichenbach, Texas.
- No, no,
that’s Luckenbach, Texas.
- So, it’s Luckenbach Falls?
- Never mind.
- It’s--
- Well, his hair turned gray
so gradually,
I didn’t notice it.
- This is like the end
of "The Shootist."
- All right, Lassie,
make your move.
( Bot whistling
and suspenseful music )
- This is gonna work, steady.
- He’s turned into Jonathan.
- Uh, uh, Russ, Russ,
this guy’s serious, Russ.
Where are you?
- Check out
your left shoe, mister.
You stepped in my pee!
( Sinister laughing )
- Alex Trebek, no!
- Gun’s turned into
a bomb pop!
- Oh, some kind of problem?
- Wait a minute.
I’ve hit absolute zero,
and I’m still walking around.
How’d I do that?
- Snausage, honey?
Now smile for me,
golden boy.
- Slowly I turned,
step by step.
- This was really cheap.
They just reversed the film.
- Now what, is he going to run
all the way back down now?
- Hey, wait a minute.
Aren’t they supposed to turn
into a big snowball
when they fall like that?
- Yeah.
- Oh, for the want of a Frisbee.
Friends?
Nice pooch.
- Never let a dog
sense your fear.
Offer him your hand.
- Oh, he’s offering
some prime butt to bite.
- Hoo-hoo.
( Suspenseful music )
- Oh, man, this is
one tough ski kid.
- Mm-hm.
- He’s in Camelot.
- Merlin, Merlin,
turn me into a bird
so I may fly from here.
- Wait a minute.
Lassie started a forest fire?
The plan’s getting
more elaborate all the time.
- Wow, and he’s turned
all the way into Lon Chaney, Jr.
( Suspenseful music )
- Oh, perfect.
This fits right into my day!
- Wait a minute. All I have
to do is hang glide down
and have a cool
Canadian club.
- Hm.
- Shep, is this supposed to be
poetic justice?
I don’t do poetic justice.
- No, Shep. I swear
it was an accident.
No, I didn’t do it.
- Guys, this couldn’t be lamer.
- No.
( SHEP GROWLING )
Don’t do it.
Don’t do it, please.
- I mean, the dog should make
his brain explode, scanner dog.
That I would buy.
- Ooh, that’d be cool.
- Please, Shep,
please, please!
Shep, no, no!
- Grizzly Adams.
- I didn’t mean it, no, no!
- You don’t know me, but-- ah!
Ow, ooh, ooh,
ooh, ow, ooh, ow.
- Oh, gun’s loose now--
thanks!
- License revoked.
- We should’ve tried
the bunny hill first.
- Heh, heh, heh, gotta laugh.
Poor bastard.
Well, gotta do my business.
- Mm, thought I’d feel good,
but I feel kind of empty.
- Folks, folks,
I had to do it.
He killed my best friend,
and he poisoned me.
I can’t testify in court.
I’m a dog!
Actually, I accomplished
quite a bit today.
- Shep! Here, Shep!
- Oh, look, they’re inside
one of those shaky snow worlds.
- Mm.
- She’s lost, Pete.
We’ll never find her.
- We’ll keep trying, son.
- So, what exactly does Tommy
get out of all this?
Hm?
- My mouth’s bleeding, Bert.
- Now that I think of it,
this doesn’t look so good.
Let’s see, what can I say?
( Wind howling )
Oh, hi, Pile On Pete.
Got some Snausages?
- And so the little fellow
found the murderous collie.
- Shep, what’s wrong?
- You’ve killed again,
haven’t you?
- It’s all right, Shep.
Sure it is.
- I didn’t do it, honest.
My ears don’t wiggle
when I’m lying.
- "The Painted Hills,
Blood Quest 2:
Some Things They Don’t Teach
in Obedience School."
- I’m having a personal
pants pile on.
- Look out, Tommy! He’s learned
the taste of human blood.
- All that was filmed
in Hollywood?
And how did they do that?
Hollywood?
- Didn’t look like
Hollywood to me.
- Oh, Pilot Pete!
Pilot with a "t".
- See, we thought
it was Pile On.
- Are our faces red?
( LAUGHING )
- I’m the ass.
- Wait, one more.
Ah, thank you.
- Well, that movie had
an interesting message.
- Yeah, that any flea bag’s
white hot vendetta
should go unchecked
until the last man lay bleeding
at the bottom of a ravine
with a crushed skull.
- Yeah, that’s what I got
out of it, too, Joel.
- Oh, come on, you guys.
Lassie was just doing
what she thought was right.
- Yeah, well, who died
and made that scabby mutt
judge, jury,
and executioner, hm?
- Well, somebody had to
bring that guy to justice.
- Oh, so is that the message,
Joel?
Take the law
into your own hands,
even if you drink from
a bowl on the floor?
- No, well-- maybe.
- Yeah, well, I say
if that DA in that jerk wadded
two-horse mining town
had any guts,
he’d bring that shaggy butcher
up on murder one
and make sure she never
nuzzled another crotch.
- Yeah.
- You know what I mean?
- Yeah, but she saw
Taylor murder Jonathan.
She was hurt.
She had to lash out.
- Oh, great.
So, by your code,
I accidentally bump my
Rottweiler with a screen door,
I wake up the next morning with
a severed cat head in my bed.
Oh, good one, Joel.
- Face it, Joel.
Your precious Lassie
should be doing
consecutive life sentences
at the Crowbar Motel.
- Yep, we’ve got a body,
we’ve got a motive.
The paw prints
and blood stains
put her at the scene
of the crime.
- We’ve got witnesses
that saw her threaten him.
We’ve got a handful of people
who saw her slip her tether
and go after him.
That cur is gonna fry, Joel,
fry.
- What about a murder weapon?
- Her own devious mind.
- No deals on this one,
Robinson.
Your client’s gonna fall.
She’s gonna fall hard.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Well, there ain’t gonna be
any deal this time.
You’re going to the mat
on this one!
Listen, let me tell you,
you’ve got nothing!
- Jail, jail, jail--
- You’ve got nothing,
and you’re scared!
Why, you’re just
blowing smoke up--
listen, I’m not gonna get sucked
into this with you guys.
Listen, Lassie is an animal and,
therefore, not subject to
the same moral or ethical code
that human beings are;
otherwise, they’d all be
arrested for public nudity.
- Oh, got a point.
- Yeah, makes sense.
- What do you think, sirs?
I’m going to bed.
- Ugh, ugh!
Frank?
Frank, Frank, Frank, no!
Hi, Joel.
Uh, Frank’s dead again.
Well, I’ve gotta go out
and buy him a new heart now,
like there’s not enough
I’ve gotta do around here.
- Ohh.
- I’m coming-- geez!
( Theme music playing )